♪
[talk radio host]
...you're saying Jews
use the blood
of Christian babies
for-for what was it?
[man calling in]
Well, for their services,
their rituals, their dinners,
so they can
take over the world.
[radio host]
For their dinners?
Oh, okay, I see.
So do they serve it in cups,
this Christian blood?
Is it a drink,
or is it more of a-a condiment,
like a-a gravy
that we can pour over food?
Because I've never been
to one of these rituals,
so I don't know.
[caller]
Are you making fun of me,
- you son of a bitch?
- [radio host] No, sir,
not at all.
You don't need my help for that.
I just want to know how I
can take over the world. Me.
[caller] See?
You're trying to bait me,
but I'm just trying
to answer your question,
you dumb kike!
[radio host]
All right, that's it,
that's enough.
Lot of antisemitism
cooking here today.
Thanks, caller,
for that load
of puritanical garbage.
You know what my problem is
with every fanatic
fundamentalist,
from the Catholics,
to the Orthodox,
to the KKK?
The one thing you all have
in common is,
and you're too ignorant
to see it,
is that you're too inept
to get by in the world,
so your-your only recourse
is to try and curtail
the enjoyment of others.
Well, there it is.
It's a great country,
but we're all still trapped
in our minds.
♪
[tinny music playing on radio]
[station ID jingle]
♪ K-O-A...
Hey, gimme, uh,
gimme that bottle.
[radio host]
I happen to believe
that most people
are decent people.
- I really believe that,
- You hear this shit?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
This fucking Jew, man.
Yeah.
Ah, fuck. Fuck him.
He needs a couple barrels
in his mouth.
Why are we out here
in the dark?
What does Bob want?
What is he fucking hunting
out in the dark?
I don't know.
- Is he hunting bats?
- ...you think the Jews...
- Maybe he wants you to join?
- ...are that organized?
Wow, I wish
we were that organized.
- Here we go.
- Until tomorrow here at KOA...
This is it up here.
Fucking safety that gun.
Thanks for listening.
This is Alan Berg,
and be safe.
[creek trickling]
[man talking loudly]
He's saying, "Get the fuck out!
Get the fuck outta here!"
I'm going, "All right,
all right, all right!"
I'm walking, it's dripping
while I'm fucking
walking out of this bar.
I'm splashing in my own piss.
She didn't think
it was very funny,
but I thought
it was pretty damn funny.
Where the fuck are we going?
I don't get it, man,
if Bob wanted to talk,
why didn't we just do it
at the fucking bar?
[gunshot blasting]
[panting shallowly]
Well, that's the problem
right there, Walt.
You talk too much.
[gasping]
Well, that shut him up.
[creek trickling]
♪
[man] Hey.
It's me.
How are you all?
I got here,
and, uh...
[exhaling]
I'm settling in,
but, um...
you know, it feels kinda empty.
So, um,
no rush, but...
when are you guys coming out?
I thought maybe, uh,
a week, two weeks...
[pills rattling]
...but you should see the...
the landscape is...
well, like they said,
it's really something.
[family passing outside,
chatting and giggling]
Thinking them girls,
they could go on, uh, hikes.
[chuckling softly]
Or not.
Well, just call.
Yeah, let me know the plans.
All right, I love you.
[distant blast of train horn]
[dispatch radio] 81, clear.
88-14, clear.
Where's the bomb, Gary?
Why didn't it go off?
I don't know.
[police radio]
...10-13, Haley Street
second and third...
Sorry, Bob.
[police radio continuing]
What do you wanna do?
- Safe going.
- You too, agent...
Keep listening.
[police radio continuing]
- Get on the fucking floor.
- [screaming]
Call your manager right now,
or you're dead!
- Don't look at me!
- Get on the floor!
- What's his name?
- Ralph.
- Say it louder!
- Ralph!
Ralph, get out here!
Where is he?
On the floor. Back up!
What's going on?
Open the safe.
Put your hands up.
Look at me.
Don't you fucking look at him,
or I'll shoot you!
Don't fucking flinch.
Ralph, open the safe,
or she's dead,
do you understand?
- Are you deaf, motherfucker?
- Ralph, I'll kill her!
- Hey!
- [woman screaming]
Tell Ralph you want to live.
- Ralph, I want to live.
- Tell him louder.
Ralph, I want to live!
Open it! Now, now, now, now!
- Okay, put the money in the bag!
- Okay.
Put the money in the bag.
Open the register right now.
- [alarm ringing]
- Who the fuck did that?
Don't fucking move.
Turn it to the fucking number.
Piece of shit,
let's go, let's go!
It's your fucking bank, asshole!
Do it!
- I'm trying!
- Come on, open it!
I will shoot you right now.
Get the hundreds first,
the big bills first!
You piece of shit,
open the fucking door.
[roaring] Now!
Move, move, move.
[police radio]
Report of a fire alarm
and no contacts inside.
4-7-1-1 en route.
We'll be right there.
Thanks, 4-7-1-1.
Help him out.
Get in the safe!
Give me the bag,
give me the bag! Let's go!
Get on the fucking floor!
Ma'am, money in the bag.
Faster!
Move! Come on!
Drop it.
Now.
[robbers inside
shouting instructions]
Get the fuck over there.
Faster! Come on!
- Move!
- Let's go!
- Let's go! Let's go!
- Give me the bag.
Get on the floor!
- Let's go!
- That's it!
That's time, let's go!
[alarm ringing, men shouting]
Keep your heads down!
Fuck.
Go, go, go!
Shoot the tires!
Don't you fucking move!
[shots blasting]
Come on!
Come on, let's go!
Get in!
[tires screeching]
[fire alarm ringing inside]
[all shouting in triumph]
Fuck!
We fucking did it!
Holy fuck! Holy fuck!
[shouting] Yeah!
[explosion banging,
brakes screeching]
Zillah?
- Hi.
- Hey.
Oh, my God, are you okay?
Yeah, no,
just a dye pack exploded.
Hey, I can't stay long,
I gotta get home.
What is that?
Take a look.
[gasping softly]
Look in the other one, too.
Oh, my God.
[gasping and laughing]
[chuckling]
[laughing and squealing]
How much is this?
He wants you to stay.
Yeah?
Want me to stay?
[in small voice] Yeah.
[laughing]
That's what he sounds like.
[kissing]
[man] Morning.
Agent Husk.
[police radio
squawking indistinctly]
Thank you.
Brought you boys some donuts.
Sheriff here?
Sheriff Loftlin...
Terry Husk.
I was surprised
to get your call.
Bureau hasn't
had a man in that office
for some time...
So I hear.
...let alone
one with your record.
KKK, Cosa Nostra?
Afraid you might
find this place boring.
Yeah,
that's the hope.
The only real crime
around here
is catching trout
without a license.
[both chuckling]
You know, you should
come over for dinner sometime.
We cook up a mean barbecue.
We'd love to have you.
When my family come in,
that'd be great.
That'd be great.
- Thank you for that.
- Fantastic.
See ya.
[Husk] I had a question
about some flyers
I keep seeing stuck up
around town.
White power, all that.
Is that the Aryan Nation?
Richard Butler
behaving himself?
How far is his compound
from here?
It's a long way up.
[Jamie] It's up by Hayden Lake.
It's not too far from here.
Oh yeah? How far?
15, 20 minutes' drive.
Just there.
Well, thank you, Jamie.
Appreciate your help.
Get back to work.
Yes, sir.
Look, I'll admit,
Butler's church is a nuisance,
but they mostly
keep to themselves.
No use poking the bear, right?
You catch bigger fish
in the river.
Have a good day.
[police radio
squawking indistinctly]
Hey, you mind if I bum
one of those?
Left mine in the car.
[whispering] You fucking shits.
[lighter clicking]
Have a good day.
[door opening and closing]
Excuse me, sir.
You left this.
My dad was in the Corps.
I'm Jamie, by the way.
I mean, Deputy Bowen.
- So, um...
- What?
So you were asking about
Hayden Lake, right?
You know
those pamphlets you saw?
That's not all they're printing.
Hey, my man.
[roaring playfully] Ah!
How you doin' today, huh?
How was school?
Can you say hello to this guy?
Can you say,
"Nice to meet you"?
- Nice to meet you.
[kissing family]
This is, uh, Agent Husk.
- Hi. Terry.
- Kimmy.
- That's my wife.
- Kimmy, hi.
They're using their press
to print counterfeit bills.
Where'd you get this?
From a friend.
His name's Walter West.
This guy I grew up with.
That's him.
He's a member
of the Aryan Nation?
Yeah, we went
to high school together,
and a few weeks back,
I ran into him at a bar,
and he was pretty loaded up,
you know, running his mouth,
and he showed me that,
and he said,
"That's just the beginning."
The beginning of what?
So, this was in June.
A bomb went off
at a synagogue in Boise,
and then in Spokane in October,
these porn stores got robbed,
and then you heard about
the bank that got hit
just up the road?
Walter says
the Nation's involved?
He says
they've gotten into explosives,
and that they're raising
a war chest for something.
Where's Walter now?
He's been missing
for two weeks.
You checking in on the family?
I called his wife, Bonnie Sue.
She hasn't seen him either,
but she doesn't want
to file a report.
You think the Bureau
would take a look at this?
In my experience,
hate groups don't rob banks.
What if it's different
this time?
[cheering] Whoo!
Well, some of the guys
got excited.
Little celebration.
Put it out.
It's not a pageant.
All right, Bob,
I'll put it out.
[applauding]
Hey, hey,
no more of that cross burning.
We don't want
the attention, okay?
Yeah.
There's almost at least
50 grand in here.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
Give every man five
as their salary.
What do you want to do
with the rest?
A tithe for the cause.
Are you Sam?
That's me.
I appreciate you
making the trip.
I'm Bob Mathews.
David told me
you had an operation here.
I didn't expect all this.
It's a start.
What else did Lane tell you?
That you're building
a militia,
needed someone to train 'em.
Mm-hmm.
He said you're the best.
That's right.
Got access to weapons?
I can get whatever you need,
but why?
You guys gonna
actually do something?
We already are.
How's $1,000 a month sound?
It's hard for an honest man
to make this in our country.
Yeah.
That's because
it's not our country anymore.
You're fucking right
about that.
You know, in every revolution,
someone has to fire
the first shot.
Want to help us do it?
Yes, I do.
Plenty more
where that came from.
Welcome.
Where you been?
Where's Clinton?
Uh, I just got him to bed.
He was asking for you.
Oh, yeah?
[grunts] Mm.
What's all that?
It's a surprise for you.
Bob...
Open it up.
[sighing]
[unzipping]
Bob...
What is this?
Wh-what...
It's for you, for our future.
Where... where did you get it?
[Clinton] Hi, Daddy.
Hey!
Oh, I'm sorry, buddy,
did I wake you up?
Hey.
Hey, come here. Hi.
Let's get you back to bed.
I told the guys they could
come by for some food.
"The Turner Diaries."
See the picture?
[Clinton] Yeah.
[Bob] That's Earl Turner...
[Clinton] Okay.
[Bob] ...and he's hiking up
through the mountains there.
He's trying to
get out of the cities.
[Clinton] Where's he going?
[Bob] Where's he going?
He's looking for
somewhere like this,
like where we live.
"My name is Evan,
and if you're reading
these pages,
then it means that I am gone.
My adventure
has been harrowing,
but I hope my story
will inspire you
to see that change only comes
when people are ready
to fight for it.
Chapter One. The Beginning.
The woods in the valley
were wet from the thaw..."
[voice fades out]
♪
[passing police siren]
[exhales, laughing]
Give him a round, Don.
How does it feel
having to call me for help?
Don't you look
so happy about it.
Oh, I'm delighted.
I did hear about your scare
in New York.
How you feeling?
Old. Trying to slow down.
All right, so you're gonna
slow down. Then what?
I'm gonna find a nice place,
have Molly and the girls
move out here,
start... putting the pieces
back together.
Terry... You forget who
you're fucking talking to?
What?
You're gonna put the pieces
back together?
That's what you're going to do?
[laughing derisively]
Oh, I've missed you, Terry.
Why'd you call me
about this case?
What you got?
I got nothing, Terry.
What do you want me to tell you?
Indulge me.
Three armored men, the driver,
all white guys, nondescript.
No security cameras inside?
No.
They dumped the car
at a dentist's office nearby.
No prints, nothing in it,
bought a car
off the classifieds for $500.
So they're patient,
they've been waiting.
Yeah, they planned it.
Took nearly 45 grand.
Anybody you like for it?
No, you?
Well, there's a kid
in the Sheriff's office
thinks it might be
the Aryan Nation.
Does that track with you?
Not particularly, no.
Eh...
No.
So, this is you
slowing down, huh?
[scoffing]
What about explosives?
We found a bomb at a porn shop
a couple days after the bank,
but it never went off.
The triggering device
was mis-wired.
Why are you asking me
about explosives, Terry?
It's good to see you.
Fuck you.
[Husk] How well do you know
this Bonnie Sue?
[Jamie] She's a nice girl.
Went to high school together.
[Husk]
If she doesn't want to talk,
remind her you're a friend.
[police radio
squawking indistinctly]
[dog barking inside]
Uncle Randy?
Yes.
Do you remember me?
Jamie Bowen.
Oh, yes.
Is Bonnie Sue inside?
Hey, can we talk?
Is he dead?
Why would you say that?
Deputy Bowen said
you called to file a report
of Walter missing,
but you never came in.
Why'd you change your mind?
Huh?
He's a drunk.
And?
He runs off.
It's not the first time
that happened.
When was
the last time you saw him?
I guess three weeks now.
[sniffling]
He went off with some guys
and he didn't show...
What guys?
Who was he with?
Names. Who are you hiding?
Who are you protecting?
What the fuck?
I'm sorry, Bonnie.
Bonnie, wait.
Wait! Wait a minute.
Hey, wait a minute.
[crying] What the fuck?
I don't know that guy, okay?
I'm sorry.
[lighter clicking]
Thought it was funny
that you joined the police.
Why?
Because you were different.
You were nice.
Aw... shit.
He was with Gary and Bruce.
Bruce? Bruce Pierce?
Yeah, I told him
he shouldn't go.
I didn't think he'd be safe.
Do you think
he fucking listened to me?
Why didn't you think
he'd be safe?
Walt had a big mouth.
What was he talking about?
How Bruce and that crew
were trying to recruit
for their group.
Crew?
You mean the Aryan Nation?
This was different.
It had a name.
You know
where they were headed?
He said they were
going hunting.
Walter took his gun.
Where?
Bruce's place?
I'm sorry.
[sniffling]
You know
not everybody around here
is born under
a white bedsheet, right?
I know you were trying to pull
some bullshit
good cop, bad cop tactic,
but you didn't have to be
such a prick about it.
It worked.
[creek trickling]
Here.
[grunting]
Careful.
♪
[grunting]
Oh, shit...
[sighing]
That Walt?
That him?
Yeah.
[bag zipping]
[police radio
squawking indistinctly]
♪
I guess we take it from here.
Whatever you need.
[Husk] You want to show me
Hayden Lake?
♪
[dogs barking]
Reverend Butler will see you.
I'll show you where we're going.
[dogs barking]
♪
[Richard Butler] We appreciate
you coming by, Agent Husk.
Not everyone in your profession
is open to participate
in civil discussion.
You see, the Church
of Jesus Christ Christian
is a place where all white men
like yourselves
come and take ahold
of their history,
a piece of their future.
We believe Christian whites
deserve a white homeland,
but we don't advocate
any of our members
breaking any laws to achieve it.
[Husk] But some do.
[Butler] Well,
you must understand that,
being in a cult
like the federal government.
Any idea...
where they are?
No, I do not.
Gary and Bruce
are avaricious young men
who lost all self-control,
and are no longer
a part of this congregation.
Mr. Bentley saw to it
personally.
And why was that?
Heard they were using our press
to print counterfeit currency,
so we asked them to leave.
Why are you looking for them?
You knew him, huh?
Walter.
So, we've heard
strays from your church
are splintering off,
forming their own groups,
and they're getting powerful.
And you're worried
Gary and Bruce are responsible.
Well, if I were you,
I'd be worried too,
because they get a taste
for power.
Get control of your strays.
Hmm?
Or this won't
be your flock anymore.
I don't know where they are,
but if I hear, I will call.
I appreciate your time.
What's that book?
[Butler] It's a book of fiction
for the children.
You should read it
sometime, son.
Thank you.
- [kids squealing playfully]
- Hey, Connie, Connie!
Let me take Krista.
- Bob needs her for the ceremony.
- No.
Hey, Krista, you want to be
in the ceremony, sweetie?
No, it's an honor.
Bob said it's an honor.
- You'll wake her up.
- You want to come, Krista?
Do not wake her up!
Bob, it's Tony Torres.
Tony. Good to meet you.
Hey, nice to meet you.
I'm Bob.
"Torres."
Is that Mexican?
No, it's...
No, no, no, no, it's Spanish.
It's actually "Taurus,"
like a bull.
Yeah, we're Spanish.
We're white, pure European.
I'm not a Mexican.
[chuckling]
Tell me about yourself.
I heard you were having
some trouble in Seattle.
Well, a bunch of spooks
took his job.
I'm sorry to hear that.
David mentioned what...
happened when you were a kid.
Do you mind if you share it
with these guys?
This spook
killed my best friend,
walked right up to him
after school,
and just...
[Bob] Shot him?
Mm-hmm.
How'd that make you feel?
I don't know what to tell.
I was lost.
I never went back to school.
I never got my diploma.
No diploma makes it hard
to find honest work,
and then you fall off, right?
I'm sorry, it's not fair,
and it's not your fault,
but...
it's going to be okay.
There's a salary here for you,
and friends,
family, okay?
You want to come join us?
I do.
Welcome.
Thank you.
- Thanks, Bob.
- Make yourself at home.
- Thank you.
- Sam.
Hey, Sam.
Nice to meet you. Tony.
- Tony, hey.
- Gary.
- Hey, Tony, welcome...
[Bob] I, as a free Aryan man,
hereby swear an unrelenting oath
upon the children
in the wombs of our wives
to join together
with those brothers
in this circle,
for we are now
in a full state of war,
and will not lay down
our weapons
until we have driven the enemy
into the sea.
It is time to reclaim the land
which was promised
to our fathers,
and through our blood
and His will,
let it become the land
of our children to be.
[applauding]
May God protect us.
[man] Amen.
[all applauding]
[printing presses whirring]
[man] You guys
will hang them up to dry.
They always gotta end up
in here, Tony.
Grab a handful.
You've gotta separate out
all the bills, all right?
10s, 20s, fives.
Gotta be in batches of 50,
and then throw
the rubber bands on 'em.
One more thing.
Bob wanted you to have this.
Come on.
Seriously?
He wanted me to have this?
Yup.
You're one of us now.
Okay.
- [chuckling]
- You did all right.
Son, I've warned you before.
You are playing with fire.
Robert, you have a gift,
a voice...
Thank you, sir.
...but do not go down this path.
We're not thieves.
You're drawing
too much attention.
From whom?
The FBI.
They found Walter's body.
We seek the same goals.
In 10 years, we'll have members
in the Congress, the Senate.
That's how you make change,
but progress takes time.
That's your problem.
You're running out of time,
and you've got nothing
to show for it.
Nothing.
You preach racial economics.
We live it.
I'm not going to be you.
You stand down, Robert.
Or what?
[truck door closes,
starts engine, drives away]
Find out
what they're up to next.
We need to clip
that boy's wings.
Hey, hey.
Hey, buddy.
- How you doing?
- Good.
Hey, Jamie,
this guy outside
brought this for you.
[Kimmy] What is it?
[Jamie] When?
[Kimmy] Just right now.
Jamie...
[revving engine]
Hey! Hey!
[Agent Carney]
Is this lead solid?
[Husk] Yeah, it's solid.
Who the fuck is he?
Hello, ma'am,
my name is Deputy Bowen.
He's the one I said
put us onto 'em.
Put us on?
What the fuck
you bring him here for?
You bringing dates
to the party now?
Stay behind. I got the lead.
[dogs barking,
distant sirens]
[knocking firmly]
[TV playing]
[pounding on door]
[woman] Who is it?
- [Carney] FBI!
- [agent] Back up!
- Back up!
- Show me your hands!
Move, move!
[Carney] Keep your hands
where I can see them!
Have you seen this man,
Gary Yarborough?
Ma'am?
[woman] He just left.
[Carney]
Who else is in the house?
[woman] No, just me.
[Carney] Turn around, ma'am.
[woman] He rented
my daughter's room
for two weeks.
He was with some friends,
real nice boys...
Carney!
Shit.
[police radio
squawking indistinctly]
[distant sirens]
[explosion]
[engine revving]
Okay, Carlos.
It's done.
All clear to go.
Okay, copy.
That's our window.
They should be coming out now.
[police dispatch]
All bomb squad units,
bomb squad units,
you are to respond ASAP,
1409 3rd Street,
Embassy Theater.
There's no report yet
of numbers.
We're en route.
[police dispatch]
Copy that. Thank you.
They're not there.
It's a distraction.
Open the fucking door!
What the...
You hear me, motherfucker?
[shouting threateningly]
- Open it now!
- Open the door!
Open the fucking door!
Get out!
Back the fuck away! Now!
Die, you motherfucker!
I said back the fuck up!
Make me do it, you...
Drop your fucking...
[shot blasting]
Shit!
[firing]
- Get out now! Move!
- Okay, okay!
- Don't make me kill you!
- I'm coming! I'm coming!
- Get out! Move, move, move!
Don't shoot!
Get on the fucking ground!
Let's go!
Get the fuck down!
- Don't look at me!
- Don't you fucking move!
[police dispatch]
Any available units,
we've got a 2-1-1 in progress.
Please respond to the south side
of Northgate Mall.
Yup, there it is.
- [tires screeching]
- Shit!
[crashing]
[horn blaring]
[tires screeching]
Terry, proceed to the Embassy!
Negative.
There's a man in the lobby
with a machine gun!
If you move
before the police get here,
he will shoot your head off!
Don't fucking move, bitch!
The bags!
Money, money! Let's go!
Fast, fast! Let's go!
Get it in the trunk!
Go, go, go! Move, move!
Don't you fucking move!
Move, and I'll blow
your fucking head off!
[Husk] There. There they are.
Oh, shit.
Last one.
[tires screeching]
[Husk] You cover me. Come on.
Go, go, go!
Come on!
Fuck... Fucking go.
[firing]
I got him, Bob.
[driving away]
[panting]
[slamming hood]
Fucking hear me?
Did you fucking hear me?
You fucker!
Did you hear me?
I'm sorry.
Huh? You hear what I said?
- I'm sorry.
- Fuck.
I'm sorry.
Fuck, fuck, fuck,
fuck, fuck, fuck!
Cocksucker!
Fuck me, man.
[tap water running]
[inhaling]
All right.
[exhaling]
[door squeaking shut]
[coughing and sniffing]
Shot of whiskey.
[sniffing]
For him, too.
Terry, I don't know
what happened, I just...
You get one pass.
That was it.
[lighter clicking]
Next time I say move,
fucking move.
[Carney] What a fucking
shit show that was.
You find the cars?
Don't ever fucking
do that shit to me again.
You're not in lead
anymore, Terry.
You don't get to run off
on your own
without fucking
telling me first!
- There wasn't time.
- There wasn't time?
- Bullshit.
- I was with Jamie.
You were with Jamie?
Well, how'd that fucking
work out for you, huh?
Considering you motherfuckers
let the target get away.
- Did you find the cars?
- Now they dumped the cars
in a lot, there's no prints.
They wiped them down,
because they had plenty
of fucking time to do it.
They had a shot on me
and they didn't take it.
- They pointed a MAC-10.
- They had a shot.
Oh, really?
Well, where were you?
They didn't take it.
Why not?
They don't want to kill a Fed.
They have a plan.
They bought the cars
from classifieds again.
[sniffing]
- Yeah.
- Paid cash.
Of course there's no prints.
They got a plan. [sniffing]
They bomb porn stores,
they bomb...
- Terry.
- ...a synagogue.
Terry, your nose is bleeding.
Excuse me.
- [Carney] Goddamn it, Terry.
- [Jamie] Can we get a napkin?
What did they get,
quarter of a million?
[sniffing] That's a fucking
war chest right there. For what?
[Carney] Wipe your fucking nose.
You're supposed to put
your head back, Terry.
I know. It's the fucking pills.
I'm fine.
Go home, Terry.
Go back to Idaho.
You said you wanted
to slow down.
Well, slow the fuck down.
I am slowing down.
No, you are not.
Is that an order?
Yes.
[bottle uncorking,
bag crinkling, drink pouring]
[call ringing]
[sniffing]
[error tone chiming]
[recorded voice]
We're sorry.
You have reached a number
that has been disconnected
or is no longer in service.
If you feel you have reached
this recording in error,
please check the number
and try your call again.
[error tones beeping]
[sniffing]
[coughing]
[neighbor voices
arguing indistinctly]
[wincing]
[breathing heavily]
♪
[coughing]
[elk grunting]
[clicking safety off]
♪
Smoke?
No, thank you, sir.
No luck, huh?
Not today.
They must be hiding.
Yeah.
[chuckling]
Maybe it's the smoke.
To what?
They like the fresh air.
They smell you coming for miles.
That so?
Mm-hmm.
Hmm.
Do you live near here?
Yeah, pretty close.
You're not from here, huh?
I'm new.
[sniffing]
You following me?
Yeah, it looked like
you could use some help.
[chuckles softly]
Have a good night.
[Husk] You too.
[man] It is my great honor
to introduce to you
a leader that has done
yeoman's work
to bring us deliverance,
Reverend Richard Butler.
[crowd cheering and clapping]
This book
holds our birthright...
but it is not one
taught in our schools,
by our elected officials.
The Promised Land
is not for the Jews...
[crowd murmuring in agreement]
...but for the true
Israelites,
the Caucasians...
[crowd cheering] Yes!
[Butler] ...and you deserve
to build that home now.
- [crowd shouting] - Yeah!
- That's right!
[Butler] Let me read you
from Zechariah, chapter ten.
[chair creaking]
[rustle of bodies turning,
chairs creaking]
Yes, Robert?
Do you have something to say?
Good morning, my brothers...
[crowd replying] Good morning.
...sisters.
[faint replies] Good morning.
It's an honor
to be here with you.
I'm proud.
If you're like me,
I'm not sure
how much more talk I can hear,
because that's all it is,
isn't it?
Talk, talk, talk.
Well, I, for one,
have had enough of just talk.
[crowd murmuring in agreement]
Now, I know how you feel.
I do.
You've lost your jobs...
...your dignity.
[crowd murmuring in agreement]
I watched my father
get knocked down
again and again,
and he never pushed back...
and they'll tell you
that's how it works.
You just have to stand there
and take it,
one link at a time,
one freedom at a time...
[crowd murmuring]
...but I won't do it.
It is time for us to fight.
[crowd replying louder] Yeah!
My friends and family,
we're here with you today
because we want you to join us
on a mission,
putting words into action.
[scattered men replying]
Yeah! Yeah!
Our brotherhood
has broken the chains
of Jewish thought
and parasitical usury.
We've stood tall
against the coloreds
who have soured our lands.
We, these,
these yeoman farmers,
are eating, breathing,
sleeping, and growing together.
They've become one mind,
one body...
- [crowd shouting in agreement]
- One race,
one army!
- [crowd shouting]
- Yeah!
We're facing the extermination
of our history,
of our very way of life!
[crowd shouting] Yeah!
Will you sit back
and allow the nation
that our forefathers discovered,
conquered, and died for
be eradicated,
or will you stand up like men
and fight to survive?
[crowd shouting] Yeah!
[Bob] Kinsmen, duty calls.
It is time to take the future
all your families deserve!
[crowd shouting] Yes! Amen!
In Metaline Falls,
we have a saying.
[sighing]
"Defeat...
never."
[crowd replying] Never...
"Victory...
forever."
[crowd shouting] Forever!
Defeat...
[crowd replying] Never!
Victory...
[crowd replying] Forever!
- [Bob] Defeat...
- [crowd] Never!
- [Bob] Victory...
- [crowd] Forever!
- [Bob] Defeat...
- [crowd] Never!
- [Bob] Victory...
- [crowd] Forever!
- [Bob] Defeat...
- [crowd] Never!
- [Bob] Victory...
- [crowd] Forever!
- [Bob] Defeat...
- [crowd] Never!
- [Bob] Victory...
- [crowd] Forever!
- [Bob] Defeat...
- [crowd] Never!
- [Bob] Victory...
- [crowd] Forever!
- [Bob] Defeat...
- [crowd] Never!
Never! Never!
[crowd chanting] White power!
White power!
[chanting] White power!
White power! White power!
White...
[kids giggling,
banging tunelessly on piano]
[Jamie] Musical chairs,
musical chairs!
[Kimmy]
Wanna play musical chairs?
[kids shouting excitedly]
Musical chairs! Yeah!
Everybody grab a chair,
grab a chair.
[kids shouting rowdily,
banging on piano]
So, I've been thinking
about these guys.
You know, it's obviously
not just a cash grab.
There's a method
to what they're doing.
You know, it's like,
maybe it's building up
to something big, you know?
Bombing porn theaters
and synagogues,
it's organized, you know,
and somebody's calling the shots
like a general...
Hey, hate to break up
the pow-wow,
but I think these guys
are getting hungry.
Should we light up the grill?
Yeah, yeah, I'll just cook
some of these hot dogs.
Yeah.
Must be hard
being away from yours, huh?
Jamie said
you've got a daughter.
Two.
When are they coming up?
[sighing deeply]
Sorry, I wasn't trying to pry,
I just...
No, no.
You two are good.
Yeah.
How did you two meet?
We met in school.
Senior year.
Hmm.
Married, had kids.
I've spent my whole life
in this house.
Grandparents, parents.
Yeah?
It's a generational house.
Lot of love in here.
Yeah.
There's something about
you coming in here,
having these talks
around the kids...
I don't like that.
You scare me.
[Jamie calling from outside]
All right, who's hungry?
[kids shouting excitedly]
Me, me, me, me!
[kids squealing playfully]
There's six steps in that book.
Recruiting, fundraising,
armed revolution,
domestic terror,
assassination.
Number six
is "Day of the Rope."
Were you gonna tell me
about this?
No.
Why not?
Because I didn't think
you'd take me seriously.
Well, I am now.
[printing presses whirring]
[radio host Alan Berg] See,
I just want to know what to do
when I get to hell,
because apparently,
as you said,
all my friends are there!
So I just want to know
what I'm walking into.
[caller] See, there you go,
you're just a kike.
You don't get it,
'cause you're just a kike.
You're making fun of something
that's sacred to Christians,
and you don't get it,
- [Berg] Oh, okay,
that's it, make it a Jew thing.
Make it about Jews.
What do you know about Jews?
Jews to you people
is some sort of
mythological creature,
some sort of beast.
You don't know anything
about the Jewish people.
It's just an easy target,
because you're too afraid
to see what's in yourself,
because you have
to have somebody to blame
for your life,
because you can't really
blame the people
that have put you
in the position that you're in,
whether it's a-a government
that doesn't care about you
and has taught you
to believe otherwise,
or it's something
within yourself...
Step five right here.
- you can't face yourself,
so it's the Jews...
Let me get him.
...but the one thing
you believe...
Let me do it, Bob.
...is that the only
really good Jew is a dead Jew,
and for some reason,
you think he cares about you.
I hear this all the time.
People say things are dirty,
things are ugly,
things are changing.
They don't like the new neighbor
on their street.
They don't like
the new synagogue in town,
and when you hear this all day,
you might think
we're so filled up with hate,
it's almost irreversible,
but this may surprise you
coming from me,
but I think people
are actually decent.
That's why they call in.
That's why they want to talk.
They want someone
to connect with.
I think people
want to give love.
They want to say,
"You're all right.
Let's sit, let's have a beer,"
but they're afraid
they won't get it back,
but I think our better instincts
will prevail,
but it's got to start somewhere.
So I encourage you
to do that tonight.
Put something good out there,
because our words, our ideas,
that's what's going to live on.
That's what matters, after all,
and that's all for me, folks.
This is Alan Berg, KOA Denver,
signing off.
Sayonara.
[exhaling]
[shots echoing into silence]
[footsteps running away]
[distant sirens approaching]
[banging on door]
[Carney] Terry, open up.
Fuck...
[Husk coughing]
[sighing]
Shit, you're really
getting the place ready
for the family, huh?
[Husk sniffing]
What?
Oh, you haven't heard.
They murdered Alan Berg.
Followed him home,
shot him 12 times,
34 wounds in all.
What was the gun?
A MAC-10.
They butchered him
like he was a fucking animal.
[happy chatting and laughing,
grill sizzling]
[laughing and giggling]
[cheering]
[Bob] Hey, everyone.
Uh, just want to say
thank you all for being here.
You know, this just means a lot.
When we first
moved here, this...
this right here,
this was the dream, you know?
Kids playing, having fun,
a big family,
in nature.
This is what it's all about,
so thank you for being here.
Thank you to God.
Um...
let's have fun.
- God bless you, Bob.
- [all clapping and cheering]
[kissing]
See that beer bottle?
Yeah.
Okay, now line it up
through these sights, okay?
Take a deep breath.
Keep this
right in your shoulder,
then, when you're ready,
you're just going to gently
squeeze that trigger, okay?
Keep looking
through the sights.
Make sure you got it,
both eyes open.
Okay, when you're ready.
I got you.
There we go.
[birds flapping]
It was close. Good shot.
Keep your weight
a little forward.
- [man] Come on, Clinton.
- Don't lean back on it.
[man] Keep shootin', buddy.
[firing]
Close.
Keep looking through
those sights, that's it.
[men cheering] Yeah!
Oh, that was it!
Yeah! Good job.
[cheering] Yeah!
Proud of you.
Yeah! That was awesome.
That was awesome.
Feel good? Was it fun?
- Nailed it, young man.
- Yeah?
Good shot, bud...
Good shot, good shot.
[exhaling into silence]
Carney...
[bustle of voices
growing around him]
Carney.
Yeah? All right, come on.
Everyone, listen up!
[voices quieten]
We've got a theory
on who this might be.
Agent Husk
is going to lay it out for you.
[police radio
squawking indistinctly]
[Husk]
The men who killed Alan Berg
have splintered off
from the Aryan Nation
and formed a new group.
They are responsible
for a series of robberies
and murders,
and they are inspired
by the doctrine in this book.
They're using this book
as a map.
Jamie.
It tells a story,
a fictional story,
of a group of white separatists
raging a race war
against
the United States Government.
There are six steps
in this book.
Recruiting, fundraising, training.
Assassination is step five.
[agent] What's six?
Armed revolution.
Large-scale
domestic terror attacks.
Poisoning city water supply,
- bombing federal buildings.
- Seizing the Capitol.
You're talking
like they're terrorists.
You got a better name?
There are plans
to assassinate the president.
This terrorist group
have a name?
In the book,
they're called "The Order."
Yeah?
I've seen that book before.
[gun store clerk]
Smith & Wesson Model 59.
[clicking chamber open]
It's clear.
[clicking chamber closed]
Works in both double
and single action.
It's heavy, isn't it?
I'll take it.
Awesome.
Anything else for you today?
Yeah, uh,
I'll take all of them.
Just need some I.D.
Sign right there, sir.
[TV playing in background]
Touchdown, Huskies!
[distant sirens passing]
[Husk shouting] You had the guy
two years ago,
and you fucking let him go!
I pulled over
some of those Nations guys,
- and they were...
- Pull the file!
They had a trunk full
of that white supremacist shit
that I was trying to control.
- [Husk muttering] Fucking idiot.
- [Carney] A fucking trunkful!
One of them
brought up that book,
"The Turner Diaries,"
and he said,
"There's no escaping
The Day of the Rope."
You know what that means?
It's the day the race traitors
are strung up in the streets.
- You know him?
- [Carney] "The Day of the Rope."
Lane, yeah,
he's from around here.
He's a fanatic.
Where is he?
I think
he's at his parents' house
- or something like that...
- Write it down.
- and his dad's a...
- Write it the fuck down!
We don't know where he is.
Last we heard,
David was in Washington,
in a place called
Metaline Falls.
There was a man there
who had some land,
who had given David some work.
This man, does he have a name?
We don't know.
Birdie,
do we still have
that photograph?
Somewhere.
Hold on.
You have children, Detective?
Uh, yeah, two daughters.
Do you love 'em?
Do you...
do you care for them?
Have you been there for them?
You...
think you have control
over who they're going to be,
but the truth is, you don't.
You try to protect them.
That's the best you can do,
but you can't
live their life for them.
It was something peculiar,
like it was two first names,
Bill Stevens,
or Mathew...
That's it.
The man's name is Bob Mathews.
Son of a bitch.
They pick up
at an overnight depot
near San Leandro, California,
then load up
for a two-day trip
from San Francisco
up the 101 to Eureka
on the coast.
It's the money run
for the entire northwest.
What's the take?
A usual run, uh,
that would be two,
two and a half million.
This could be four.
Hi...
Hi.
I'm Debbie.
Oh, okay.
[chuckles nervously]
Good for you.
Thanks.
My job is to hit the windshield
if they don't get out...
Go back, go back, go back.
Start, which car are you in,
where are you sitting?
Excuse me, Bob, can we talk?
Uh, now?
Yeah.
Okay.
Just keep running it.
Load up, okay?
- Yeah.
- All right.
What are you meeting about?
Hmm?
Look, you know...
You know I can't-I can't say.
[murmuring of men talking,
clicking of guns]
What about her, does she know?
Because people talk.
Is she having your baby?
You have nothing
to worry about.
You know that, right?
I love you.
All I care about
is you and Clinton,
okay?
Okay? Hey. Okay?
- You all right?
- Yeah.
I love you.
Come here. It's all right.
Come here.
[gun clicking]
[bustling with busy agents]
[Husk] Father was
an appliance store salesman.
Loses his job,
they grow up in a trailer,
blame it on all immigrants.
Subscribes to John Birch.
Got arrested in '73
for lying on his W-4.
That's straight out of
the anti-tax playbook.
Joins the National Alliance,
- whose founder...
- William Luther Pierce.
...writes "The Turner Diaries,"
then he leaves that group too.
It's a pattern.
He's a radical.
He's a radical, but he can't
deal with authority.
Look at his father,
look at Butler.
Clever fucker.
I met him.
You did?
When?
A few weeks back.
He was casing me.
We found him.
Metaline Falls,
Bragg Creek Road.
All right, we got the address,
let's go.
♪
Go, go, go! Move!
- Over here!
- Go around the back.
Move!
Clear! Clear! Clear! Clear!
♪
[police radio
squawking indistinctly]
Breaker, breaker,
passing me now.
♪
Let's get 'em.
[engine revving]
[tires screeching]
- Where is he?
- I don't...
- [grunting]
- You don't know?
- I don't know.
- Oh, really?
Goddamn, what are you doing?
We can't take her in.
Do you know what he did
in Denver?
I got nothing to say!
- Jo, Jo...
- Clinton!
We can't take her in.
Jo, Hey, hey!
Get off of me!
Where are you taking my child!
- Jo, hey!
- You sit the fuck down!
We need her here.
We keep eyes on her.
I'd be careful
who I'm protecting,
- you dumb Nazi bitch.
- Clinton?
All right, take it now.
Go, go, go, go, go.
[tires squealing]
[pumping shotgun]
[brakes screeching]
Move! Let's go!
Come on, let's go!
[men shouting]
Get out or you're dead!
On the floor!
Move, move, move!
Is anyone in the back? Come on!
Open the door!
Throw out your gun,
and come out with your hands up!
Get out now!
[gunfire, guard screaming]
Go!
- Down, down!
- Don't shoot!
Move, move!
[grunting]
Take it! Let's go, let's go!
Don't fucking move!
Go!
[men shouting]
Here! Go!
Faster!
Go, go, go!
That's four minutes gone!
Let's go!
Take him out!
[distant sirens approaching]
That's the four minutes, guys,
let's go!
- Let's go!
- Cops!
Let's get out of here!
Fucking pigs!
- Pack it up!
- Go, go!
[gun clattering]
Go, go, go!
[engines revving]
[sirens wailing]
[brakes screeching]
Whoo-hoo!
[panting, laughing]
We're good, boys.
How much they get?
3.6 million.
What does that buy?
It buys an army.
Where... where are we at
with the gun?
The trace on the gun?
[agent] We're still waiting.
Waiting on what?
They couldn't pull any prints,
but ATF traced the serial number
to a store in Missoula.
- We're working on a name.
- Where?
Missoula.
- Missoula?
- Yeah.
Do you know how far
Missoula is from here?
[agent] Two and a half hours.
So why the fuck
are we fucking waiting?
I-I made the call.
[Jamie] Why isn't anybody
driving to Missoula, huh?
Tell me.
Tell me, Mr. FBI.
- Hey.
- [Jamie] Jesus...
I mean, you're the fucking FBI!
Got a fucking point.
[door slamming]
[Husk] You all right?
[lighter clicking]
That was fucking bullshit,
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Get in the car.
[Jamie] FBI...
You know, it used to be
every day
I was running home to see them.
And now...
this.
This is all I think about.
I worked organized crime.
Lucchese family,
you heard of them?
Mm-mm.
Nasty fuckers.
In my last year,
I worked New York.
There were two dozen murders,
and I needed to get inside.
I had no witnesses,
so I recruit this girl,
this nanny of one of the bosses.
She was younger than you.
Smart.
Persuaded her to wear a wire.
But I don't know, they,
how they found out,
but they did...
and we found her...
head in the East River.
Found her arms,
her legs.
Never found her body...
...and I never got anyone
for that.
Why are you telling me that?
Got a name on the gun.
[Bob] Zillah?
Where have you been?
We've been calling all over.
[whispering] Oh, hi.
That's your dad.
Oh, my God.
This is your daughter.
I'm really sorry
she's not a boy.
She's b...
You're beautiful.
You want to hold her?
It's really easy.
She's sleeping, huh? Hi.
Hmm?
She's so perfect.
- She's so little.
- I know.
[baby cooing]
You got her?
It's okay. Hi.
We gotta learn a lot.
Oh, my gosh...
[baby crying]
It's okay, it's okay, it's okay.
It's all right,
it's all right...
Yeah.
Oh, my God, she's beautiful.
[voices echoing indistinctly]
Bob give you this?
It's cute.
You all wear these?
Fuck you.
[prison locks buzzing]
Give me those.
Alan Berg.
[patting]
Get this.
They shot him 12 times.
Two in the face,
two in the neck,
six in the left arm,
one in the abdomen,
traversed his liver,
came out his stomach,
and one in the back.
That's a hard way to go.
[sliding along bench,
slamming bars]
[spluttering and wincing]
You didn't pull the trigger,
but you know
where they are, right?
Now you're gonna fucking
tell me where they are,
or I'm gonna lean on you
so hard,
you're not gonna get
off the fucking floor...
- Terry...
- You understand me?
What?
Oh, fucking shit.
[Carney] Your goddamn nose.
[panting]
[exhaling]
[sighing]
What are you doing here?
Hmm?
26 years I've done this job.
26 years.
Every mobster,
every Klansman,
they got one thing in common.
They're all trying
to blame someone else.
You think Bob's loyal to you?
You-you think he's your friend?
Hmm?
You're a tool to him.
He's using you. You're a pawn.
How do you think
your friend's going to react
when he finds out
you're a Mexican?
Where is he?
There's a number you call
if you ever got bopped.
Leave a message
at the switchboard,
and they call back
with instructions
telling you how to get out.
You remember the number?
[clattering of diner dishes,
flattop sizzling]
[engines rumbling up outside]
[rumbling engine idling]
Tony.
[Husk] Is Bob driving?
Negative, not him.
Nobody goes in
till we have eyes on Mathews.
They're leaving.
Keep your distance,
three cars back.
I'm following.
[sports broadcast
playing on radio]
Good to see you, buddy.
Anybody know you're here?
Huh?
No.
Good.
That's real good.
[police dispatch radio
squawking indistinctly]
Should I call it in?
Not till we see him.
[tap water running]
Come on in.
[Bob] Have a seat.
[turns off tap water]
[sighing, door closing]
I'm really sorry
about the trouble you got into.
I'm going to help you
out of it, but, um...
well, I'm gonna
need your help first.
Man, they don't know I'm here.
Did you tell them anything?
No, nothing.
I did what you said.
Well, it's not...
They ask about the gun?
No.
No gun.
Did they ask about Berg?
I want to...
I want to believe.
I do.
Why would I rat on you?
You guys are...
You guys are my friends, no?
Are we friends?
Are we?
You know?
Yes.
Because real friends,
they come clean
when they make mistakes.
If you told them something,
it's fine, okay?
But I do need to know the truth.
Just tell me
what you told them.
Come on.
We can trust each other.
Just tell me.
Whatever happens,
I'm here for you.
If you're honest now,
it's all going to be okay.
[whispering] Thanks, Bob.
It's okay.
[crying softly, sniffs]
We're brothers.
I didn't say anything, Bob.
Nothing at all?
I'm sorry about the gun.
It's on me.
Will you forgive me?
[chuckling softly]
[sniffs] Yeah.
- Yeah?
- Sure.
Okay.
[sighing]
It's gonna be all right.
[Husk] That's him.
[Carney over police radio]
Husk, do we have a visual?
Do we have a visual on Mathews?
Call it in.
Wait, wh-what are you doing?
We've got eyes on Mathews
at the Capri Motel.
We need backup here now.
[TV playing]
Don't fucking move!
Show me your hands!
Show me your fucking hands, Bob!
Show me your fuck...
[shot blasting]
- Holy shit!
- [distant screaming]
Okay.
[grunting]
[car honking]
[tires squealing]
Jamie!
Take the room!
[Carney] Jamie, get back!
Get away from the door!
Don't shoot! Don't shoot!
Freeze! Fucking freeze!
Hey! [gunfire]
Move!
[sirens approaching]
[Carney] Get the fuck down!
Tony, you all right?
- [slamming]
- [Tony] Yeah, I'm good.
[Carney] Don't move!
Don't you fucking move,
you piece of shit!
Fuck you.
[panting]
[voices inside]
[pigeons cooing]
[Husk panting]
Jamie!
Where is he?
Slow the fuck down!
[firing until his gun empties]
[neighborhood dogs
barking and howling]
[Jamie clicking his empty gun]
[Husk firing and panting]
[firing]
Oh, no, no, no, no.
No, no, no, no.
No, no. All right.
Put your head down,
put your head down.
Jamie, no, no, no, no.
[grunting, spluttering]
Keep your head down.
Oh, shit.
Jamie, look at me, look at me.
Come on.
[Jamie spluttering]
Jamie, look at me.
Look at me, look at me.
Jamie.
Shit...
[choking and spluttering]
Jamie.
Look at me.
[gasping]
Hey...
[sniffing]
[zipping]
[police radio
squawking indistinctly]
♪
Willie, come in.
Now, please.
Get inside.
[crying]
Found this
in Bob's hotel room.
[Debbie]
Do you know how we met?
He put an ad in the paper.
"Looking for an intelligent,
mature woman
to share my life and my land."
About a hundred women responded,
but out of all of them,
he chose me.
Hmm.
But I couldn't have children.
Bob said he didn't care.
He was excited to adopt,
but I know it still mattered.
He wanted his line to continue.
Debbie, none of this is for you,
or Clinton.
You don't know.
I do.
All the sacrifices,
the work...
the women.
He can justify it all
with the cause
he's fighting for.
End of the day,
it's all about him.
Believe me.
You know that.
Right now,
he's planning an attack
that will kill
hundreds of people.
I need your help to find him.
Debbie, do not
protect this man
just because you think
he's some saint.
I know he's not a saint.
[toy car wheels rolling]
I never been there before,
but there was always a plan
if they had to run.
There's a house.
[Husk] Thank you.
He won't know it was you.
Doesn't matter.
You won't take him alive.
[chuckling]
♪
So, was it worth it?
[Husk] What?
The work,
women,
sacrifices?
What do you think?
[chuckles ruefully]
But we've always worked
very well together.
[typewriter clacking]
Where's Bob?
Finish your fucking cereal.
We've gotta get out of here.
[typewriter clacking]
Hey, Bob.
Hey, Bob, you ready to go?
Hey.
Hey, Bob,
I got the truck outside.
What is this?
Declaration of war.
Who am I sending it to?
Congress,
the House of Representatives,
the White House,
"New York Times,"
Denver, Denver news.
Everyone.
Why?
It's happening.
The war has begun.
Fuck. There's no fucking army.
Everybody's gone.
[Bob] Cattle die,
kinsmen die,
I too shall die,
but the one thing that I know
that never dies,
it's the fame
of a dead man's deeds.
♪
[typewriter clacking]
Bob, let's go.
We gotta go now!
Let's go, let's go, let's go.
They're fucking everywhere.
[panting]
[police radio
squawking indistinctly]
[Carney] Is he in there alone?
Fuck you.
[geese honking]
[police radio
squawking indistinctly]
[Carney] Send 'em in.
[Husk] Bring him out alive.
Alive.
[window shattering]
[gas hissing]
[grunting]
[smashing]
Let's go, let's go.
[police radio
squawking indistinctly]
♪
[rapid gunfire, agents shouting]
[gasping]
[distant machine gun fire]
[agents shouting and grunting]
[muffled shouting]
[grunting]
Go, go, go!
Pull 'em out!
[exchanging gunfire]
[agents shouting]
- Go, go!
- They're coming out!
We've got wounded!
Come back!
Move it, move it!
Take cover!
[panting]
[vomiting and coughing]
It was a mistake.
It's a mistake.
He's not coming out.
- Come on, let's go.
- He's not coming out.
You'll burn him alive.
[breath hollow through gas mask]
[panting, gasping]
[coughing]
[breath wheezing]
[sizzling and igniting]
Shit.
[distant banging
of structure collapsing]
[coughing]
[flames roaring]
Let's go.
It's done. Come on.
Bob!
[ammunition exploding]
[bullets ricocheting]
[coughing]
[clicking safety off]
♪